hi everyone i'm karan and welcome to
currency on the stock on focus for today
is ICICI Bank
and it's three billion dollar stake sale
so guys and news have come has come
today that ICICI Bank ways to sell its
stake of three billion dollars so by
ways I mean people speculate so this
article is it's exactly why Bloomberg
and Bloomberg speculated that the
private sector lender wants to raise
about three billion dollars through a
share sale as early as September and
actually ICICI Bank does not only need
this money it has a good level of tier
one ratio which is about thirteen point
four and actually it is law it is also
enviable as in a lot of banks are
jealous about ICICI Bank having such a
high tier one ratio I would explain you
what is a Tier one ratio but I would
like to continue about news first and
the second point about the news is this
capital can help ICICI bolster its
growth after this corona virus pandemic
ends so this not only can help this
capital not only can help ICICI Bank in
these turbulent times but also can help
ICICI Bank ramped up scale of the
businesses increase the loan book after
the corona virus pandemic edge so as I
promised you I would explain you the
Tier one ratio so Tier one ratio is a
core measure of bank's financial
strength so tier 1 ratio basically
measures how strong is the finances of
the bank how strong is the bank's
financial strength a high ratio of the
bank indicates that the bank can absorb
a reasonable amount of losses without
the risk of failure this is that if in
turbulent times the bank is faced with a
lot of stress that means a lot of
borrowers default on the loans that Bank
and absorb reasonable amount of losses
without the risk of failure the base of
three requirement states that the bank
should have it
six percent Tier one ratio and as you
can see ICS a bank has almost double of
that requirement
it's about thirteen point four percent
and that's why it's quite an vehicle a
lot of people hate seeing ICICI Bank a
lot of banks hate seeing ICICI Bank
having a very high tier one ratio so
this is pretty much a comparison of
different banks in their t1 ratios
actually ICICI Bank doesn't have the
highest tier one ratio for Dagmara Bank
has the highest t1 ratio in India after
that HDFC Bank and ICICI Bank and then
Axis Bank however a lot of private banks
are particularly not enviable about
ICICI Bank stay one ratio it's the
public sector banks that are enviable
about the ratio I will give you more
detailed analysis HDFC Bank has 16 per
16.4% tier 1 ratio x-axis Bank has about
one about thirteen point two four
percent Tier one ratio which is lesser
than ICICI Bank four-time winner has the
highest ratio of seventy point seven and
SBI has a ratio of nine point seven
seven so SBI being the biggest psu Bank
and the PS biggest PSU lender it having
Tier one ratio of nine point seven seven
in basically highlight the bad debts of
PSU banks as you know PSU banks are the
point managing that money and have
really high NPS and I have really low
tier one ratio so this is this is pretty
much it this graph pretty much shows you
the different Tier one ratios and gives
you an understanding about the standing
of ICICI Bank among other banks the bank
has already raised three thousand Kuro
in the past two months through stake
sales in its insurance subsidies it's
it's sold part of its takes in ICS a
potential life insurance and ICICI
Lombard general insurance
moreover India's second largest private
bank will be joining its peers in
seeking capital to
expand its lending business and betting
on an economic recovery once the
pandemic subsides
it's not only ICICI Bank who is looking
to raise capital it is a lot of banks
are looking to raise capital HDFC Bank
Kotak Mahindra Bank so that's what
saying it's saying that along with ICICI
Bank lot of its peers are seeking
capital to expand lending business now
apart from expanding its lending
business
why is ICICI Bank raising money when it
has a good capital and you can see that
trumps that of its peers so what this
question is asking is why does ICICI
Bank after a raise money it has a good
tier 1 ratio it has a good captain attic
adequacy ratio and it's doing better
compared to its peers and why always
need to raise money it has already
raised 3,000 kuroh some stake sales
previously so why is 3 billion dollars
so I will give you the reasons behind
this so analysts believe that this
capital can enable the bank to not just
survive the pandemic risk but also
growths booked and gain a market share
ICICI Bank has stressed loan of about
sixteen thousand six hundred and
sixty-eight crores under watchlist
by what I'm buy what I mean by watchlist
is ICS a bank is watching loan pool of
about sixteen thousand come over because
they fear that these loans might turn
into NBA's because these are desperate
times and a lot of borrowers are likely
to default these exposures come from
commercial real estate non banking
finance companies and small businesses
like in my previous videos I have told
you how housing finance companies or non
banking based finance companies are at a
particular list I told you how LIC
Housing Finance is doing poorly how
indiabulls Housing Finance is doing
poorly how the Tata Motors finance
coming into financing arm of Tata Motors
at finances auto loans is doing poorly
so basically any company that is fine
see money into other people they are
doing poorly because there has been a
downturn in the industry and a lot of
borrowers are at watchlist because they
are not likely to pay their debts in the
lag zero default so they are you know
something to consider and commercial
real estate loans real estate industry
again as a downturn so that's why those
loans are also under watchlist
the bank has CELTA is difficult it is
difficult to assess impact on asset
quality you do moratorium on the loans
however the lender has given enough
provisions to cover the risk from
arising the pandemic so the bank is
basically saying that as of now a lot of
people are not paying the EMI is because
of the RBI guideline about giving relief
to people who have taken loans in giving
em eyes because of which since people
aren't giving EMI is you can't
differentiate between people who are
likely to default and people who are
likely to pay there am eyes after this
moratorium of loans gets up gets lifted
so this is this is what i see i say bank
says this it's difficult to him to
assess the impact on asset quality so
once this situation is over ICS a
banking judge the impact more clearly
and you know the stakes L can help raise
its provisions explained you what
provisions are before provisions is
basically surplus cash you have that can
absorb the losses from people who are
defaulting on debts so those are
provisions meanwhile the banks share
prices have dropped by about seven
percent in the last two trading sessions
pricing of potential increase in supply
of shares so since ICICI Bank would be
selling you know shares so there has
helped you increase in supply of the
free float available free floating
shares available the market that non
promoters can buy and since a lot of
shares would be available the markets
and the supply would increase and the
demand is yet the same because of demand
supplied or discrepancy the share prices
have fallen however global analysts
take this as a good
News and expect a 25 26 percent upside
this was not my opinion so I'm not
recommending it to buy ICICI Bank I'm
just giving you a take on what global
analysts think so now let us look at the
share price of ICICI Bank ICICI Bank
ICICI Bank made a high of about I'd say
five hundred fifty rupees in the in the
last six months and after this pandemic
it had dropped to historic low of two
84-piece as of now ICICI Bank is trading
as rupees the onion peru piece which is
pretty reasonable to the Hyatt maid and
the Lord had made previously
and I would say ICS a bank is at
reasonable level to buy and he should
kind of wait and watch for some time we
should wait for the market to be less
volatile but if you guys have an SI P in
any if you want to put an SME in ICICI
Bank it can give you a good time to
average down as it because I believe I
see a say banks price should go up in
the long run it is a good bank it is
India's second largest bank second
largest lender it's a good private bank
it has good ratios it has to it has less
amount of NPS compared to PSU banks so
if you want to buy a PSU bang forget
about buying PSU bank and rather buy
ICICI Bank HDFC Bank or Kotak Mahindra
Bank and this is a pretty good level I
would I won't recommend buying but you
should keep a track on the price of
ICICI Bank and maybe in western si P if
you can so guys this is pretty much it
about ICICI Bank and I hope you liked
the video please like please press the
like button if you liked the video and
please subscribe to my channel if you
want more such videos in the future
thank you so much bye bye